(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-10T09:08:03.899357",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんな、今日は見に来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for coming to see me today!
お誕生日になりましたよー！
It's my birthday!
誰かが捨ててしまった 昨日を拾い上げ
Picking up yesterday that someone threw away,
がむしゃらに手を伸ばした
I frantically reached out my hand,
答えをつきつめて
Searching for the answer,
何を手に入れても
No matter what I get my hands on,
満足することはない
I am never satisfied.
複雑にからんだ 心の隙間から逃げ出せ
Escape from the void of my tangled heart!
そうさ make a treasure
That's right, make a treasure!
錆びついた時の中に君の声を聞く
I hear your voice within rusted time.
このまま届けたい 光の中
I want to reach you right now, inside the light,
君が待ってる そう信じてるから 今すぐに
Because I believe you're waiting for me, right now!
全てを使い果たした
Having used everything up,
未来は擦り切れて
My future is worn out,
ためらいがちに選んだ 夢さえきしみ出す
Even the dreams I hesitatingly chose begin to creak.
憂鬱な日常 抜け出すことさえしない
I don't even try to escape my gloomy daily life.
そんな君の側で 待ち続けるのはごめんだから
I'm sorry for keeping you waiting by my side, so...
そうさ make a treasure
That's right, make a treasure!
錆びついた鏡の中自分を探して
Searching for myself inside a rusted mirror,
この手でつかみたい どこにいても
I want to grasp it with my own hands, wherever I may be.
君が待ってる そう信じてるから
Because I believe you're waiting for me,
今すぐに
Right now!
今日はシンデレラのお披露目もありますよ！
Today is also Cinderella's debut!
最後まで盛り上がっていってねー！
Let's get hyped all the way to the end!
何を手に入れても
No matter what I get my hands on,
満足することはない
I am never satisfied.
複雑にからんだ 心の隙間から逃げ出せ
Escape from the void of my tangled heart!
そうさ make a treasure
That's right, make a treasure!
錆びついた時の中に 君の声を聞く
I hear your voice within rusted time.
このまま届けたい 光の中
I want to reach you right now, inside the light,
君が待ってる そう信じてるから 今すぐに
Because I believe you're waiting for me, right now!
そうさ make a treasure
That's right, make a treasure!
錆びついた鏡の中 自分を探して
Searching for myself inside a rusted mirror,
この手でつかみたい どこにいても
I want to grasp it with my own hands, wherever I may be.
君が待ってる そう信じてるから
Because I believe you're waiting for me,
今すぐに
Right now!
空を駆けて 未来へと
We'll dash through the sky to the future
ぎゅっと手を取り合い はしゃいでた丘
Tightly holding hands, we played on the hill
今日もあの日と変わらない 風のにおいがした
Today, too, the wind smelled just like that day
いにしえの思い出 翳れない瞳たち
"Ancient memories," "unclouded eyes,"
かすかに呼び戻されて 交差する記憶
faintly calling back and intersecting memories.
大地と太陽 どんな時もすべてを 抱きしめた
The earth and sun embrace everything at all times,
大切な君を 守りたいよ今
I want to protect the precious you right now.
涙こぼれたら
When your tears overflow,
そっと風になる
they will softly turn into wind.
頑なに閉ざした 扉なら開け欲しいさ
If there's a stubbornly closed door, I want you to open it.
さあ飛び出して 未来へと
Come on, let's fly out to the future!
憎み合う心と 愛し合う心って
Hearts that hate and hearts that love
同じくらい誰かのこと ずっと想っている
are thinking of someone just as much all the time.
それは鏡の中に映し込んだ自分が
That is the self reflected in the mirror,
ふたつの心を持って 生きているように
living as if it had two hearts.
出逢えた仲間は 優しさにすべてを変えていく
The friends I met turn everything into kindness.
大切な人を 守りたいよ今
I want to protect the people precious to me now,
ずっとひとりきり 強いふりしてた
having always been alone and pretending to be strong.
譲れない願い 重ね合わせいっしょにさあ
Unspoken wishes, overlapping together, come on,
新しい未来へと
to a new future!
もしも闇に心とらわれて 光求められている誰かがいたなら
If someone's heart is seized by darkness and they're searching for light...
大切な君を守りたいように この手差し伸べる勇気を持てたら
Because I want to protect the precious you, if I could have the courage to reach out my hand...
大きな力を 与えられた今なら
If I'm given great strength now,
そう旅立てる 未来へと
that's right, I'll set off for the future!
結び合う心と 愛し合う心と
Hearts that connect and hearts that share,
心をあて 同じくらい誰かのこと
matching our hearts, thinking of someone just as much
すうっと想っている
all the time.
それは神様の中に 映し込んだ自分が
That is the self reflected deep within God,
ふたつの心を持って 生きているように
living as if it had two hearts.
大切な人を 守りたいよ今
I want to protect the people precious to me now,
生きてるように 出逢えた
living as if... having met them.
仲間は 優しさにすべてを
My friends turn everything into kindness,
変えていく 大切な人を
changing it. The precious people...
守りたいよ今 ずっと一人きり
I want to protect now, always all alone
強いふりしてた 譲れない願い
pretending to be strong, unyielding wishes
重ね合わせいっしょにさあ 新しい未来へと
overlapping together, come on, to a new future!
譲れない願い 重ね合わせ一緒にさあ
Unspoken wishes, overlapping together, come on,
新しい未来へと
to a new future!
あの空を駆けて 未来へと
We'll dash through that sky to the future!
ソラちゃん改めて おめでとう
Sora-chan, happy birthday once again!
ありがとう めちゃめちゃおいしそうよ今日は
Thank you! It looks super delicious today!
もしも闇に心とらわれて
If your heart is caught in darkness,
光求めている 誰かがいたなら
and someone is searching for the light...
誰かが描いたなら 大切な君を
If someone dreamed it, the precious you...
守りたいように この手さしだせる
like wanting to protect you, I can reach out this hand
勇気を持ちたい 大きな力を
and I want to have the courage. Great strength
与えられた今なら そう旅立てる
if given to me now, that's right, I can set off
未来へと 大きな力からを
to the future! From that great strength...
与えられた 今ならさあ 旅立ってる
if given to me now, come on, we are setting off
未来へと あの空を駆けて 未来へと
to the future, dashing through that sky to the future!
つまらないデイイズももう散々ね！
Boring days are already over!
奇跡願っているだけの人生
A life just wishing for miracles
watch me do-do-do-do-do
呪術秘中トリック無しのマジック
Magic without any tricks or secrets
I wanna be free! だってまだ序盤だし
I wanna be free! Because I'm still at the start
(The party ain't started)
Hey タクシー ちょっと宇宙まで
Hey taxi, take me to space for a bit
秒針は音を立てて夜を急かす魔物のように
The second hand ticks loudly, urging the night like a monster
人生は一瞬にして溶ける魔法
Life is magic that melts away in an instant
それならば駆け抜けて想い通り！
If so, run through it just as you wish!
おしゃまな馬車飛び乗って drivin'
Jump on the playful carriage and start drivin'
あたしは大変身 メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great transformation, make-up!
我儘のままに華麗に注意
Be careful not to get caught up in selfishness
洒脱な街で dancin'
Dancing in a stylish city
左様なら グッバイ劣等感
If that's the case, goodbye inferiority complex
何時かは喝采 クラップ オーディエンス
Someday, applause from the audience
皆々御歌和あれ！
Everyone, join in!
いやあ、ちょっとね、コメント欄もね
Man, the comment section is...
なんかちょっと商店しちゃったみたいで (笑)
Looks like it totally short-circuited haha!
ちょっとね、上がっちゃったようですね (笑)
It seems like it got a bit too excited haha!
え、まずね、1曲目は『stellar stellar』という曲で
Well, first off, the first song was "Stellar Stellar"
いやあ、超かっこいい曲がすごく苦手で
Man, I'm really not good at super cool songs,
え、苦手なの？ 本当に苦手
Eh, you're not good at them? Really not good.
めちゃくちゃかっこよかったよ。でも、それを頑張って歌ってみようと思って1曲目にしました。
It was super cool though. But I wanted to try my best to sing it, so I made it the first song.
はい！
Yes!
そして次、空にかける橋はですね、めあちゃんが星のめあちゃんで、そして私も星のモチーフがある
And next, "Bridge to the Sky", Mea-chan has star motifs, and I also have star motifs,
ということで、ええとなんか、あの、お互いね、そう、空に関わるじゃないですか、星って言って。
so... um, we both, well, relate to the sky in a way, because of stars, right?
だから、空になんか、ちなんだ感じで、で、なおかつ希望にあふれてるような曲を一緒に歌いたいなと思って。
So I thought I'd love for us to sing a song together that's related to the sky, and also overflowing with hope.
え、嬉しい！ 嬉しい！
Eh, I'm so happy! I'm so happy!
いや、なんかさ、あの、ちょっと私はね、先に聞いたんだけれども
Yeah, you know, um, I listened to it beforehand,
歌い終わりとかも、あ、そう、だからね、こだわってくれて
and even at the end of the singing, ah right, so you were so particular about it—
そう、希望に満ちたところとか、なんか未来へ向かうところを、どうしてもめあちゃんに歌ってほしくて、めあちゃんの歌割りを決めた後に自分の歌割りを決めたっていう感じでした。
Yeah, places filled with hope, and places heading towards the future, I really wanted Mea-chan to sing them, so I decided my singing parts after deciding Mea-chan's singing parts.
あ、そうなの？
Ah, is that so?
めあちゃんにここを歌ってもらおうから先に決めました。
I decided first that I wanted Mea-chan to sing this part.
聞きました、皆さん！
Did you hear that, everyone!
聞きました？ 皆さん
Did you hear that? Everyone.
聞きました？
Did you hear that?
え、もって言われてね
Eh, when you say "more",
嬉しい。うん。あとね、あの、やっぱり
I'm so happy. Yeah. Also, um, after all,
同じビクターでね、出してるわけじゃないですか。
we're releasing under the same label, Victor, right?
そう、だから歌いたかったんでしょ、ずっと。やっとだね！ やっと！ 嬉しい！
Yeah, so you wanted to sing together all along. Finally! Finally! I'm so happy!
せっかくのお誕生日だから、呼んじゃった！
It's a special birthday, so I invited you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
私にとってもご褒美です。
It's a reward for me too.
そんなことないでしょ！ ありがとう！
No way! Thank you!
嬉しい！ 嬉しいね、私も嬉しいよ！
I'm so happy! I'm so happy, I'm happy too!
嬉しいしか言ってない今日。
You've only said "happy" today.
ね、いいよ、だって。今度また一緒に何かやろうね。
Well, that's fine. Let's do something together again next time.
え？ やろう！
Eh? Let's do it!
聞きました、皆さん！ 全部、全部聞きました？ 聞きました？ ありがとう！
Did you hear that, everyone! Did you hear all of it? Did you hear it? Thank you!
いや、こちらこそ本当にね、忙しい、なんか来た、なんか業務連絡みたいな。
No, seriously, you're so busy... it felt like some kind of official work notice.
違います、違います、違います！ そういうつもりじゃなかったから。
No, no, no! That wasn't what I meant!
じゃあね、この後もね、たくさんね、歌うと思うので、楽しみにしてます。
Well, you'll be singing a lot more after this, so I'm looking forward to it.
頑張ります！
I'll do my best!
新小もね、もちろんありがとう。
And of course, thank you for the new clothes.
じゃあ、この後も頑張ってね！ ありがとう！ ねぇ、でした！ またね！ ありがとう！
Well, do your best after this too! Thank you! Yeah, that was it! See you! Thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
お水を飲みまっしゅ。
I'm gonna go drink some water.
そして、ステージパワーアップなんです！
And the stage has powered up!
見て！ 春だから！ 春だから、桜だよねやっぱり。春だから。
Look! Because it's spring! It's spring, so it's cherry blossoms after all. Because it's spring.
まあ、それ以外にも1曲目的な意味でも桜にしたかったっていうのがあるんですけど、
Well, aside from that, in terms of the first song's meaning too, I wanted cherry blossoms,
あと、ここに星があったりとか、ここね、とか、なぜかぬぬが増えてる、とか、
and also, there are stars here, and here too, and somehow there are more Nunu characters,
ちょっとね、いろんなバージョンアップがあるんですよ！ ぜひぜひそちらのね、ステージも楽しみながら見てももらえたら嬉しいです。
there are various version upgrades! I'd be so happy if you enjoy looking at that stage as well.
次なんて思います？
What do you think is next?
イェーイ！
Yeah!
では、次の曲に行きましょうか。
Well then, shall we move on to the next song?
次の曲聴いてください。
Please listen to the next song.
シュガーソングとビターステップ！
Sugar Song and Bitter Step!
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
Used to this crazy turmoil like a catastrophe,
こんな日常を平和と見間違う
Mistaking this daily life for peace.
Rambling coaster揺さぶられながら
Rambling coaster, shaken around while,
見失えないものはなんだ?
What is it that I cannot lose sight of?
平等主義原理主義の概念にのまれて
Swallowed by the concept of egalitarian fundamentalism,
心までがまるでエトセトラ
Even my heart is just like an etcetera.
大嫌い 大好き ちゃんと語らなきゃ
Hating, loving, we've gotta talk it out properly,
人形とっかえ引っかえ変わらないし
Interchanging dolls doesn't change anything,
宵街を行く人かかりは
The crowds walking the evening streets,
嬉しそうだったり 寂しそうだったり
Some looking happy, some looking lonely,
コントラストが五線譜を飛び回り
Contrasts fly around the musical staff
歌とリズムになる
And become song and rhythm.
マーマレードにシュガーソング
Marmalade & sugar song,
ピーナッツ&ビターステップ
Peanuts & bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
Sweet and bitter, it's making me dizzy.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Head south-southwest and keep the party going,
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It's going to be a night that startles the world.
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel top-notch, reflecting in a chain.
蓋然性合理主義の正論に揉まれて
Tossed in the face of probabilistic reason,
僕らの音楽は道具に成り下がる?
Will our music be reduced to a mere tool?
こっちを向いてよ 背を向けないでよ
Don't turn your back on me, face this way,
それは正論にならないけど
Though that might not be a valid argument.
祭囃子のその背後で
Behind the sounds of the festival music,
昂ったままの人 泣き出してしまう人
Those who remain excited, those who start to cry,
多分同じだろう
They're probably all the same.
でも言葉にするようなものなら拙劣が極まり
But if put into words, it's just poor taste,
最高だって
Saying it's the best.
シュガーソング 幸せってビターステップ
Sugar song, happiness is a bitter step,
死ねない理由をそこに映し出せ
Show the reason why you can't die right there.
惜しかったって等速で明日は来ちゃうけど
Tomorrow comes at a constant speed regardless,
脳内天気予報のアップデートを果したなら
If you've updated your brain's weather forecast.
もっと遠くまで 座標の距離が誇らしい
Further away, proud of the distance in coordinates,
世界中を驚かせ続けよう
Let's keep on surprising the whole world.
マーマレードにシュガーソング
Marmalade & sugar song,
ピーナッツ&ビターステップ
Peanuts & bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
Sweet and bitter, it's making me dizzy.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Head south-southwest and keep the party going,
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It's going to be a night that startles the world.
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel top-notch, reflecting in a chain.
騒々しい 虚騒が粋をひそめても
Even if the clamor and noise hide away,
正論に意味がなくなっても
Even if right arguments lose their meaning,
鳴らし続けることだけが
Only continuing to play our music
僕たちを僕たちたらしめる証明になる
Will prove what makes us who we are.
急いで
Hurry up!
膜面のシュガーソング ピーナッツ&ビターステップ
Marmalade & sugar song, peanuts & bitter step,
生きてく理由をそこに映し出せ
Project the reason for living right there.
北極星とは到底 そうの距離が誇らしい
So proud of that distant trajectory,
世界中を驚かせ続けようよ
Let's keep on surprising the whole world.
マーマレードにシュガーソング
Marmalade & sugar song,
ピーナッツ&ビターステップ
Peanuts & bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
Sweet and bitter, it's making me dizzy.
脳内天気予報のアップデートを果したなら
If you've updated your brain's weather forecast,
騒々しい 虚騒が粋をひそめても
Even if the clamor hides away,
正論に意味がなくなっても
Even if right arguments lose meaning,
鳴らし続けることだけが
Only continuing to play our music...
マーマレードにシュガーソング ピーナッツ&ビターステップ
Marmalade & sugar song, peanuts & bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
Sweet and bitter, it's making me dizzy.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Head south-southwest and keep the party going,
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It's going to be a night that startles the world.
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel top-notch, reflecting in a chain.
Goes on 一興去って一難去ってまた一興
Goes on, one fun thing, one hardship, then another,
一興だってまた一興
Every twist and turn is just another fun ride.
笑って笑って
Smile and laugh all the way!
ではあ！しがみよるのです！こんにちはぁー！
Well then! Cling to me! Helloー!
なんか終わったあとに緊張することってあるんだね
You know, sometimes you get nervous after it's over, huh?
今緊張！あんなにノリノリで歌ってたのに
I'm nervous right now! Even though I was singing so hyped up just a moment ago.
というわけでね、歌唱でね、結構ね、一緒に...結構久しぶりではあるもんね
So that's why, in our singing, it's been quite a while since we sang together, hasn't it?
そうなんだよね。それでいったら...
That's right. If you put it that way...
なんか前フェスとかではね、一緒にあったりしてたんだけど、その時にね、いい声だな、一緒に歌いたいなってずっと持ってて
Back at previous festivals and stuff, we'd occasionally see each other, and back then I kept thinking, "What a great voice, I want to sing with her."
えー！嬉しい！いい！嬉しい！え、ありがとー！
Eeh! I'm so happy! Good! So happy! Eh, thank you!
それで、なんか、もしよければ出てくれないかっていう話をしましたね。
So, like, I talked to her about whether she'd be willing to appear if she was okay with it.
でも、速攻でオッケーしてくれたよね。
But you gave me an ok right away, right?
本当に！やったやったやった！やったやった！ねね！
Really! Yay, yay, yay! Yay, yay! Hey, hey!
そう。うん。これを歌ってみたを出してたんんだよ。
That's right. Yeah. I had released a cover of this song.
それがあまりにもよかったから一緒に歌いたいなって思って
And it was so amazingly good that I thought I wanted to sing it together.
そしたらさ！嬉しい！ガチだから！
And then! I'm so happy! For real!
もうまさか一緒にね、セッションできると思わなかったから、いやー！
I never thought we'd be able to do a session together, so man!
もうさ、はまっちゃった！
I got totally hooked on it!
ほんとね！もともとハモりも入れてたんだけど、めちゃくちゃハモれるから、なしにして、
Seriously! I originally had harmonies in there, but since we can harmonize so well, we made it without harmonies,
本番やったらもうぶわってやりたいってなって。ほら、コーラスに徹するので、サビは
and when it came to the actual performance, we wanted to go all out. Look, since I'm focusing on chorus, the chorus part...
今日の主役が歌ってくださいよってってなったんですよね。
"Please, today's birthday star, you sing it," is what happened.
うん。だからね、私もだから、あのハモりできたから、あの、あそのえのちゃんがメインのところはやったんだけど、
Yeah. So, you know, I was able to harmonize too, and so Eno-chan took the main parts,
そこ以外の場所交互にやろって言ったら、や、いーよ！いーよ！って言われて
and when I suggested taking turns for the rest, she said, "No, it's fine! It's fine!"
意志を感じたよね自分のなかで。かっこたる意志があった。かっこたる意志が！
and I could feel her strong resolve. There was a firm resolve in her!
いや絶対今日はメインだけを歌わせるぞって
"I will definitely make her sing only the main today!"
嬉しかったでしょ、もう呼んでくれて。やあ、こちらこそ来てくれてめちゃくちゃ嬉しかったよ。
You must have been so happy she invited you. Man, I was so happy you came here.
本当に、なんかステージもめちゃくちゃ豪華でさ。
Really, like, the stage was also super gorgeous.
あれは一個持って帰っても許されるの？
Are we allowed to take one of those home?
なにを？
Take what?
あの上に、あ下のやつでもいいよ。あ、このこの子たち？この子たちは増えるものだから持って帰っても大丈夫！やったー！
Those upper ones... oh, the lower ones are fine too. Oh, these kids? These kids multiply, so it's totally fine to take them home! Yay!
待って、プレゼント渡さずにプレゼントもらっちゃった。間違えたっ！
Wait, I got a present without even giving mine. Oops!
大事にしてあげてください。うちのぬぬぬぬのを。大事にしちゃおうかな。やったー！
Please cherish it. Our nu-nu-nu-nu. I think I'll cherish it. Yay!
え、でもね、もう時間ぽいんだよね。
Eh, but you know, it's about time, isn't it?
じゃあ、スクショ撮ろう！
Then let's take a screenshot!
え、スクショ撮っていいの？いいよ！いぇーい！いっぱい撮って！
Eh, can we take a screenshot? Sure! Yay! Take lots of them!
いぇーい！嬉しい！嬉しいわ！
Yay! I'm so happy! So happy!
あ、でも、お、でもさ、そろそろちょっと群れの移動にさ、群れの移動もちょっと待ってもらってるから、そろそろね、行かないといけなっぽいんだよね。
Ah, but, oh, but you know, pretty soon we gotta move the flock, and since the flock is waiting a bit for us too, it seems like we gotta go soon.
大変な時に来てくれてありがとう！全然！ごめんね！
Thank you for coming at such a busy time! Not at all! Sorry!
いや、こんどこそ！でもね、この後移動中に絶対ね、かわいいかわいい噛むしなの新作絶対見るから！
No, next time! But you know, during the move afterwards, I'll definitely check out the cute cute Kamushina's new work!
うん！もうじいってみながら歩く！じいってみて！あぶないあぶない！
Yeah! I'll walk staring intently at it! Stare intently! Careful, careful!
だめだよ！あ、そうだよね。群れの目の前だからさ。そうだよね。
Don't do that! Ah, that's right. Because we're right in front of the flock. That's right.
じゃあもう移動で止まって見ますからね、しっかり。そそそ、皆さんたくさんもっと祝ってあげてくださいね。
Well then, we'll stop during the move and look properly, yeah. That's right, everyone, please celebrate her even more, okay?
はーい！というわけで、おめでとう！ありがとう！
Oookay! And with that, Happy Birthday! Thank you!
またね！また遊ぼね！
See you again! Let's play again!
うんうん！ふふふっ。二人もお祝いに来てくれちゃった！
Yeah yeah! Fufu. Two people even came to celebrate!
嬉しいね！
I'm so happy!
やあ、でも次はここじゃなくてステージの真ん中で歌っちゃおうかな？
Man, but next time, maybe I should sing right in the middle of the stage instead of here?
チュッチュルチュ チュルチュルチュ
Chu-chu-lu, chu-chu-lu
こういうわけね！
That's how it is!
ふだんとはちょっと違うかもしれないけどみて新衣装なんですよ！
It might be a little different from usual, but look, it's a new outfit!
っていうことかっていうもん、みんな最後まで見てねー！
That's right, everyone, make sure to watch until the very end!
同じ未来を見たい あの夢手にしたい
I want to see the same future, and make that dream mine.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo!
Running with our different hearts, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
Sprouting in a pitch-dark place no matter where I looked,
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
my eyes were captured by a tiny glimmer of hope.
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my trembling heart of anxiety just right,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I mustered up a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up," I move forward.
苦しいときももう私はひとりじゃないから
Even in painful times, I'm no longer alone.
だからもっと夢追いかけたいワクワク止まらない
That's why I want to chase my dreams more, my excitement won't stop.
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination.
アクセスしてみたい後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to access it, and I won't let there be any regrets.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo!
Running with our different hearts, go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光を現実に届けるよ
bring an unseen light into reality.
いつも聞こえるエールをここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers I always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
it makes me want to search for a new light.
君の笑顔は保存して進む
Saving your smile, I move forward.
悲しいときに見返すよ力が湧くから
Looking back at it when I'm sad gives me strength.
胸を張って夢追いかけたい奇跡のストーリー
Proudly holding my head high, I want to chase my dreams in this miraculous story.
一緒に作ろう終わらない夢を
Let's create an endless dream together.
誰一人欠かせない愛が舞ったこの世界
In this world where love dances, with not a single person missing,
それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
let's color it with our different hearts.
悲しいときも寂しいときもある信じ合えるものがある
There are sad and lonely times, but we have things we can believe in together.
忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
Without forgetting, I want to keep this heartbeat ringing.
終わらない世界に溢れ出す笑顔達
Smiles overflowing into an endless world,
憧れの舞台立ちたいらしく輝きたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams and shine in my own way.
時には涙してまた笑い合いたい
Sometimes shedding tears, and smiling together again.
同じ未来を見たいあの夢手にしたい
I want to see the same future, and make that dream mine.
踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
Let's take a miraculous step forward.
息切らせて夢追いかけたいワクワク止まらない
Catching my breath, I want to chase my dreams, my excitement won't stop.
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination.
アクセスしてみたい?後悔なんてここにない
Want to access it? There's no room for regrets here.
それぞれ違ったココロで作るworld
Building a world with our different hearts.
いつかできた傷あとに
On the scars we made someday,
涙が染みちゃうのなら
if tears start to seep in,
笑顔のバンドエイドをあげるから前を向いてさあ行こう
I'll give you a smile bandage, so look forward and let's go!
深く深く愛してよ
Love me deeply, deeply.
何もかもが思い出や
Everything is a memory.
恋は怖くないでしょ
Love isn't scary, right?
あなたと私なら
If it's you and me.
強く強く抱きしめてよ
Hold me tightly, tightly.
あの夜にさよならを
Say goodbye to that night.
いつものここで待ってるよ
I'll be waiting right here in our usual place.
だからもっと恐れずに愛してね
So don't be afraid anymore, and love me.
同じ未来を見たいあの夢手にしたい
I want to see the same future, and make that dream mine.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo!
Running with our different hearts, go!
Shiny Smily Story (2022 ver.)
[Song Title: Shiny Smily Story (2022 ver.)]
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
Wherever I looked, in the pitch black, it sprouted
ほんの小さな希望に
By just a tiny spark of hope
この瞳奪われた
My eyes were captured
不安で揺れる心を上手くチューニングして
Tuning my wavering, anxious heart just right
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I mustered up a tiny bit of courage
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up" and moving forward
苦しいときも、もうわたしはひとりじゃないから
Even in painful times, I'm no longer alone
だからもっと夢追いかけたい ワクワク止まらない
That's why I want to chase my dreams more, my excitement won't stop
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that surpasses imagination
アクセスしてみたい 後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to access it, I won't let you regret it
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go!
Run with our different hearts, go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光を
Deliver a light you've never seen before
リアルに届けるよ
Right into reality
いつも聴こえるエールは ここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers I always hear right here
また新しい光を 探したくなるよ
Making me want to search for a brand new light
君の笑顔は保存して進む
Saving your smile as I move forward,
悲しいときに見返すよ力が湧くから
Looking back when I'm sad gives me strength.
胸を張って夢追いかけたい 奇跡のストーリー
Wanting to puff out my chest and chase my dreams, a miraculous story
一緒に作ろう 終わらない夢を
Let's create an endless dream together
誰ひとり欠かせない 愛が舞ったこの世界
In this world where love dances and no one can be left out,
それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
Colored by our different hearts.
みんな今日は見にきてくれてありがとう お誕生日の祝いも嬉しいよ！
Thank you everyone for coming to see me today, I'm so happy for the birthday celebration too!
悲しいときも 寂しいときも
Even when I'm sad, even when I'm lonely,
信じ合えるものがある 忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
There is something we can believe in together, I want to keep making this heartbeat echo
終わらない世界に溢れ出すよ笑顔達
Smiles overflow into an endless world.
憧れの舞台立ちたい らしく輝きたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams, shining like myself,
時に涙してまた笑い合いたい
Shedding tears at times, and smiling together again.
同じ未来を見たい あの夢手にしたい
I want to see the same future, grasp that dream,
踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
Let's take that miraculous step forward.
息切らして夢追いかけたい ワクワク止まらない
With my breath catching, I want to chase my dreams, my excitement won't stop,
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that surpasses imagination,
アクセスしてみたい？ 後悔なんてここにない
Want to try accessing it? There is no regret here,
それぞれ違ったココロで作る world
Creating a world with our different hearts.
というわけで、ちょちょるとシャイニー・スマイリー・ストーリー、2曲続けて歌いました！
And with that, I sang "Chocchoro" and "Shiny Smily Story" two songs in a row!
まずは こちらの師匠の お披露目になりますね どうですか？
First off, this is the unveiling of this master here, what do you think?
ね、見て見て見て見て、これさ まずこちらの衣装ではスカートに星がつくんです よ。
Look, look, look, look at this, first of all, with this outfit, stars attach to the skirt.
あと足ですね 足。こうブーツ。こっちに羽もあるブーツ。
And then there's the feet, the feet. Boots like this. Boots with wings on them too.
そしてこうふって上がってくるとこっち側が白系、こっち側がピンク。
And then as you come up, this side is white, and this side is pink.
ねね、ちょっとアシンメトリーだけどとっても可愛い感じ。全体的にねピンクですね。
Hey hey, it's slightly asymmetrical, but it has a really cute feel. Overall, it's pink, you know.
そしてここね、ここリボンもありますし、あとね
And here, there's a ribbon here too, and also
お耳にはアンキモがついていますよと。
On my ears, Ankimono is attached, you see.
そしてリボンもピンク！全部ピンク！可愛いしょ？
And the ribbon is pink too! All pink! Isn't it cute?
うしろの、サクラとも
Our Sakura-themed...
相性がぴったり！
Outfit match is perfect!
ねえ見て、こっちのステージもすごくない？
And look, this stage is amazing too!
えー、めちゃくちゃ可愛い！わあー、すごい！
So, so cute, waaaah! Amazing!
いぇーい！
Yay!
で、ここでポーズを決める私は、
So, for deciding the pose here,
みんなこれを撮って、たくさんポストしてね！
everyone please take lots of posts!
ふふっ
Haha!
なかなかね、そらの配信ではし、気恥ずかしい感じだけど、
It's kind of hard to do in Sora's streams, but...
おっ、トレンドにしたの？
Oh! It became a trend?
みんなのおかげだ！
All thanks to everyone!
ありがっちょ、ありがっちょ、ありがとうー！
Arigatcho, arigatcho, arigatou!
この衣装ではしゃぐなって感じする？
Do you feel like getting hyped up in this outfit?
ごめんね！いっぱい、いっぱいぞうやいて、ありがとう！
Sorry! Give me lots and lots of smiling items, thank you!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
今も言ったとおり、この後もいろいろあるから、
As I said just now, there's more to come after this,
まだ見てね。お水飲もう。
so make sure to keep watching! Drink some water!
開いて。
Open!
では、そろそろ次の曲に行きますか？
Now then, shall we move on to the next song?
次の曲聴いてください！
Please listen to the next song!
Grip!
青色に散らばる 七つの星よ
Seven purple stars scattering in the blue,
それぞれに今 想いは募り
bringing each thought together.
打ち砕かれて 愛を叫んだ
Breaking through, crying out for love.
逃げ出す事もできずに 夢にしがみつく
Unable to escape, clinging to our dreams,
イカサマな日々などにはもう負けない
we won't lose anymore to tricky days!
目覚めよう この瞬間を
Wake up to this moment!
やがて僕らを 取り巻くであろう
Soon we will be surrounded by...
むせかえるようなリアルな日常
a reality that chokes us up.
大切なものは...何だっけ?!
What is... most important?
贅沢な世界の中に 見え隠れする 永遠の破片(かけら)を
Shards of eternity hiding in this luxurious world.
さわって つかんで ぼくらの今をきっちり歩いていこう
Touch and seize it, let's walk our present path step by step.
「後悔はしない」と、先へ進んだ
"No regrets," we pushed forward.
笑うか、泣くか? 幸か、不幸か?
Will we laugh? Will we cry? Happy or unhappy?
結局 今も ワカラナイけど
Even now, we still don't really know,
変わり始めた未来に怯(ひる)む事はない
but we won't flinch at the changing future!
それが人生の醍醐味というものでしょう
That must be the essence of life.
ギリギリ aを生きる僕らの出した答えが
The answer we found living on the edge,
間違っていたとしても 思い込みでもっ
even if mistaken, it's still our conviction.
強く願えばいい 本物になれる日まで
If we wish hard enough, until the day we become real—
冷酷な世界の中で 潰されそうな 愛情の芽吹きを
In this cruel world, love's budding is about to break,
さわって つかんで ぼくらの今にしっかり刻み込もう
so touch and seize it, engraving it firmly into our present.
目覚めよう この瞬間を
Wake up to this moment!
やがて僕らを 取り巻くであろう
Soon we will be surrounded...
むせかえるようなリアルな日常
by a reality that chokes us up.
大切なものは...何だっけ?!
What is... most important?
贅沢な世界の中に 見え隠れする 永遠の破片(かけら)を
Shards of eternity hiding in this luxurious world.
さわって つかんで ぼくらの今をきっちり歩いていこう
Touch and seize it, let's walk our present path step by step,
最後に、笑うため ぼくらの今をきっちり歩いていこう
just to be able to smile in the end.
後悔しないと 先へ進んだ
If we don't regret, we can move forward.
笑うか、泣くか? 幸か、不幸か? 結局今もわからないけど
Laugh or cry? Happy or unhappy? Still don't know, but...
変わり始めた未来に怯む事はない それが人生の醍醐味というものでしょう
There's no hesitation in the changing future, that's life's true thrill!
ギリギリ生きる僕らの確かな価値観が間違っていても思い込みでも強く願えばいい
Living on the edge, the answer we found, even if it's wrong...
本物になれる日まで
Strongly wishing to become the real thing someday!
冷酷な世界の中で潰されそうな愛情の芽吹きを
In this cruel world, love's budding is about to break,
さわってつかんで僕らの今にしっかり刻み込もう
touch and seize it, and engrave it firmly into our present!
目覚めようこの瞬間を
Wake up to this moment!
やがて僕らを取り巻くであろうむせかえるようなリアルな日常
Soon we will be surrounded by a reality that chokes us up...
大切なものは何だっけ?!
What is... most important?
贅沢な世界の中に見え隠れする永遠のかけらを
Shards of eternity hiding in this luxurious world.
さわってつかんで僕らの今をきっちり歩いていこう
Touch and seize it, let's walk our present path step by step.
最後に笑うため
Just to be able to smile in the end,
ぼくらの今をきっちり歩いていこう
let's walk our present path step by step!
目覚めようこの瞬間を
Wake up to this moment!
青いに散らばる 七つの星よ
Seven stars scattered in blue,
それぞれに今想いは募り 打ち砕かれて愛を叫んだ
feelings yearning within each of us as we cry out for love.
逃げ出す事も出来ずに 夢にしがみつく
Unable to escape, we cling tightly to our dreams.
イカサマな日々などにはもう負けない
We won't lose to these fraudulent days anymore!
目覚めましょう この瞬間を
Let us awake to this very moment,
やがて僕らを 取り囲むであろう むせかえるような リアルな日常
that will soon surround us in our stifling everyday life.
大切なものは…何だっ?!
What is truly important...?!
僕らの今を きっちり歩いていこう
Let's firmly walk our present path.
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
信じ合う仲間と一緒に
Together with trusted friends,
頂点の景色を上げよう 終わらない青春に
let's reach the view from the top in an endless youth!
夢中感 自信は捨てて へいじゃみ みんなで揃えば来るじゃんじゃん
Toss aside self-doubt! When we all gather together...
光るスイート木漏れ日落ちて
Glowing sweet sunlight filtering through trees,
青春が感じている遊びあちゅー
youthful days felt like playtime!
成長した姿を見せたい
I want to show my grown-up self!
理想は完璧 半端はもっと絶叫で
My ideal is perfection, half-measures with louder screams!
大切な思い出 たくさんあるけどね まだ
We have so many precious memories, but still...
感情に浸ってる暇はない
there's no time to get lost in emotion!
今世紀最大の夏が始まる
The greatest summer of the century is beginning!
想像の果てにある高み
Reaching the heights at the edge of our imagination,
勝ち取った景色は尊い
the scenery we won is so precious.
逃げるな限界の壁越えて
Don't run away, cross the wall of your limits!
僕らはまだチャレンジャー
We are still challengers!
冷たい木漏れ日に溺れたって
Drowning in the cool sunlight filtering through trees,
微かな望みを手繰り寄せるように
as if groping for a faint hope.
期待外れだと誰かが嘆く 痛いと痛いがいつも戦う プライドだけを頼りに抗う 自分を信じたい
Resisting with only pride, wanting to believe in ourselves!
努力は報われる 笑いたい奴は笑ってろ
Efforts will be rewarded, let those who want to laugh, laugh!
感情に浸ってる暇はない 今世紀最大の夏が始まる
There's no time to dwell, the greatest summer begins!
反響が足りないもっともっと 後悔はさせない
The resonance isn't enough! We won't let you regret it!
想像の果てにあるあの高み
That height at the edge of imagination,
勝ち取った景色は尊い
the scenery we won is so precious.
逃げるな限界の壁越えて
Don't run away, cross the wall of your limits!
僕らはまだチャレンジャー
We are still challengers!
お邪魔しまーす！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Excuse us! Happy birthday!
お疲れ様！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Good job! Happy birthday!
話しちゃった
I started talking.
誰が呼ぶかみたいなの見たかったの
I wanted to see who would call who.
しかも今なんと私たちトレンドにということで！
And what's more, we're currently trending right now!
やった！
Yay!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
初めてかもトレンド入ったの
It might be my first time trending!
え、そうなの？
Oh, really?
え、おめでとう！全力で！
Um, congratulations! With all my might!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
いや、みんながね、こうやって盛り上げてくれるからだね。
Well, it's because everyone hyped us up like this.
えへへへ
Hehe.
ありがとう！ありがとう！みんなもありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you everyone too!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
すごい！
Amazing!
え、そしてですね、グリップは、
And also, for "Grip",
Baeちゃんと歌ったんだけど、ずっとね、
I sang it with Bae-chan, but she kept saying
一緒に歌いたいて言っててんだよね。
she wanted to sing it together all this time.
そう、めっ
That's right, ve--
初めて話した時からさ！
Ever since we first talked!
はい！
Yes!
それを叶えたくて呼んじゃいました。
I wanted to make that come true, so I invited her.
反動とももう尊敬がね、もう...
And the backlash and my respect...
ありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you so much!
なになに何？大丈夫？
What, what, what? Are you okay?
土下座？
Dogeza?
びっくりした！
That surprised me!
楽しかったですね！いや本当にありがとう！
We had so much fun! Seriously, thank you!
そしてですね、祭ちゃん若いわ！
And also, Matsuri-chan is so youthful!
やっぱ今回の衣装も「アイドル」って感じの衣装にしてさ、
After all, this time's outfit is also very "idol"-like,
ねえ！
right!
やっぱみんなでアイドルっぽい曲も歌いたいだと思って！
I thought we all wanted to sing an idol-like song too!
この曲めっちゃ好きなんだよね！
I love this song so much!
めっちゃあがる！
It gets me so hyped!
あのね、裏話するとね、
You know, as a behind-the-scenes story,
あの、2人のほうがずっと練習して緊張してた。
those two had been practicing and feeling nervous the whole time.
えい、えい、えい！
Yay, yay, yay!
でもまあね、あの、ゲストパートなまのことってやっぱ珍しい。
But well, you know, having guest parts live like this is pretty rare.
そうね！ちょっと緊張感がね！
That's right! There was a bit of tension!
そうだから、自分のほうはさ、いいんですけど、
So, as for me, it's fine, but...
頑張んなきゃみたいな！
"I gotta do my best!" like that!
いやいや全然！
No, no, not at all!
みんなクソッて言ってきますね、ありがとうございます！
Everyone's saying "Damn it", thank you very much!
おい、なんでクソッて入ってて！
Hey, why did "damn it" get in there?!
なんてクソって入ってて！
Why did "damn" get in there!
いやそんな感じでね、やっぱりね、ホロのメンバーとも一緒に、
Yeah, like that, after all, with Hololive members together,
でも私ってさ、なんか生放送にこだわりすぎちゃってるからさ！
but for me, I tend to get too obsessed with live broadcasts!
だから、いいことよ！
So, that's a good thing!
そう、だからね、今日もね、みんながね、こうスケジュールを合わせてきてくれたわけだよ。
So, that's why today too, everyone adjusted their schedules to come.
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
当然ですよ！
Of course!
当たり前だ！
Naturally!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
後ろもありがとう！
Thank you to the back too!
ね、みんなで写真も撮っちゃおうよ！
Hey, let's take a photo together too!
やった！
Yay!
えっとね、どんなポーズ？
Let's see, what pose?
どうする？なんか...
What should we do? Something like...
きゅんきゅんきゅんきゅんみたいな！
"Kyung kyung kyung kyung" or something!
Baeちゃんだけなんかピースして遠くにいるけど！
Only Bae-chan is doing a peace sign and standing far away!
なんでなんで？なんかおたみたいになって！
Why, why? It ended up looking like an otaku!
混ざっちゃった、オタクみたいになって！
It got mixed up, like an otaku!
どら先輩は前、あ、大丈夫！
Dora-senpai was in front, ah, it's okay!
ありがとう、まだ生きてる。
Thanks, I'm still alive.
私たち、ホロライブだよ！
We are Hololive!
ホロライブポーズ？これがあのホロライブポーズ。
Hololive pose? This is that Hololive pose.
なんか違う？なんか感覚。
Something's different? Some feeling.
なんか面白くなっちゃうんだろ。
Why does it end up being so funny?
これさ、重りのせいかもしれない！
This might be because of the weight!
え、これもうだってこうじゃない？
Eh, isn't it already like this?
こうなっちゃうんだから！それは違う！
It ends up like that! That's wrong!
ちょっと違う！やってた！
That's different! I was doing it!
いやでもね、こういうふうにワイワイとやるのが本当久しぶりなので、
But you know, doing lively things like this is so rare,
とっても嬉しい！本当に出てくれて...
I'm so happy! Thank you so much for coming...
いいな、いいな！あ、しまった！ありがと！
That's nice, nice! Ah, oops! Thank you!
まいたん、ありがとう！
Mai-tan, thank you!
めっちゃ喜ぶじゃん！嬉しい！
You're so happy! I'm so glad!
なんか貰ってばっかりだな！
It feels like we're always just receiving things!
こんなもらってるのに！
Even though we're getting this much!
というわけで、
And so,
ゲストパート終わる時間...
the guest part time is ending...
えー！ここにも床に...
Eh! Right here on the floor...
床になるの！
Becoming the floor!
連れて帰るもよし。
You can take them home if you like.
いいの？いいの？いいよ！
Is it okay? Is it okay? Sure!
ちょっと思い出！
A little memory!
ちゃんと踏んで貰って、祭り踏んであげるよ！
Make sure to step on them, I'll step on you, Matsuri!
いいです、いいです、いいです！なんかいいです。
It's fine, it's fine, it's fine! It's kind of nice.
というわけで、今日は来てくれて本当にありがとうございました！
So, thank you all so much for coming today!
こちらこそありがとうございます！
Thank you very much to you too!
この後も楽しんで！
Enjoy the rest of the show too!
いや、にやからメンバーで嬉しかったな！
Man, being with the Ni-yaka members made me so happy!
それじゃあ、次はまたあっちのステージに戻って、
Well then, next, returning to that stage over there,
歌おうかな！何があるかな！
shall I sing? What will happen?
前略、電子の日は今日も
Greetings, the electronic sea is today too
晴れ、時々雪、ところによりパフェ
Sunny, sometimes snow, parfaits in places
前人未踏のテラバイ島で
On the uncharted Terabyte Island,
またどこかのあなたを = 待機中 =
waiting for you somewhere once again—
偶然だって必然のうちは
Even if it's chance, while it's destiny,
受信送信は見えない糸でしょ
Receiving and sending are connected by invisible threads, right?
断然こっちがしっくりくる
This definitely feels much more right.
enter×space で escape
Escape with enter × space
The Boooom!ここは0と1の楽園
The Boooom! This is a paradise of zeros and ones.
The Boooom!広く深い世界から見つけだしして
The Boooom! Find me from the wide and deep world.
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrical Surfin', Surfin'
こちらに来て来て
Come on over here,
好いも狂いもいただきます
I'll take all your affection and madness.
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin', Surfin'
手と手と取って取って
Taking hand in hand,
白昼夢中 夢中で踊り明かしましょう
Lost in a daydream, let's dance the night away.
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Unbeatable smile, stirring up the media
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
Wanting to know that secret, mysterious
抜け出しているところ彼女のエリア
That elusive side, part of her controlled area
完璧で嘘つきな君は
Complete and perfect, all you say is a lie
天才的なアイドル様
Dear miss genius idol
今日何食べた？
What did you eat today?
好きな本は？
What book do you love?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
Where do you go when you go out to play?
何も食べてない
Haven't eaten anything
それは内緒
It's a secret
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
Always acting vaguely no matter what you're asked
淡々だけど燦々と
So unconcerned, although brightly glowing
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
Secrets seeming hidden yet visible are sweet as honey
あれもないないない
Nothing, nothing, nothing
これもないないない
This isn't here either
好きなタイプは？相手は？さあ答えて
What is your type? Any partner? Answer this
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からなくてさ」
"I don't have any idea how I could love anyone"
嘘か本当か知り得ないそんな言葉にまた一文字堕ちる
Unable to know truth from lies, I fall for those words again
また好きにさせる
Making me fall in love once more
誰かが目を奪われていく 君は完璧で究極のアイドル
Everyone's eyes are stolen by you, the ultimate, perfect idol
金輪際現れない
Unrivaled, will not appear again
一番星の生まれ変わり
The brightest star reborn
ああ、その笑顔で愛してるで
Ah, using that smiling face to say "I love you"
誰人も彼も虜にしていく
Captivating everyone all around
その瞳がその言葉が 嘘でもそれは完全な愛
Your eyes, your words—even if untrue, that is complete love
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yes, yes, she's very special
我々はハナからおまけです
We've been extras from the start
お星様の引き立て役Bです
Just supporting starlets in the background
全てがあの子のお陰なわけない
It can't be that it's all thanks to her
シャラクサい 妬み嫉妬なんてない
Out of line, no jealousy or envy
わけがない これはネタじゃない
No way, this is no joke
だからこそ許せない 完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
That's why I can't forgive an imperfect you
自分を許せない 誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I can't forgive myself, accepting no one stronger than you
誰かが信じ崇めてる まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Worshipped by all, truly the strongest and invincible idol
弱点なんて見当たらない
No weaknesses to be found
一番星を宿している
The brightest star resides in you
弱いところなんて見せちゃ駄目だ
Showing any weakness is forbidden
知られたくないことは隠して
Hide what you don't want known
唯一無二だ抜け出しちゃいやいや
One and only, don't you dare slip away
それこそ本物の愛
That is true love
得意の笑顔で濁すマリア 隠しきるこの秘密だけは
Blurring with a practiced smile, keeping this secret hidden
愛してるって嘘で摘むキャリア これこそ私なりの愛だ
Building a career on "I love you" lies—that is my way of love
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア ルビーを隠したこの瞼
Flowing sweat, pure aqua; rubies hidden beneath my eyelids
歌い踊り舞い私はマリア そう嘘はとびっきりの愛だ
Singing and dancing, I am Maria; yes, lying is the greatest love
誰かに愛されたことも誰かのこと愛したこともない
I've never been loved by anyone, nor loved anyone myself
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること信じている
I believe that someday my lies will become the truth
いつかきっと全部手に入れる 私はそう欲張りなアイドル
Someday I'll get it all, I am such a greedy idol
等身大でみんなのことちゃんと愛したいから
Because I want to truly love everyone as my true self
今日も嘘をつくの この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
I lie again today, wishing for the day these words come true
それでもまだ君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
Even so, I still couldn't tell you and you alone
ああ やっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is definitely no lie
愛してる
I love you
はいはいあの人は特別です
Yes, yes, she is special
我々はハナからおまけです
We've been extras from the start
お星様の引き立て役Bです
Just supporting starlets in the background
全てがあの時のお陰なわけない
It can't be that it's all thanks to her
シャラクサい 妬み嫉妬なんてない
Out of line, no jealousy or envy
わけがない これはネタじゃない
No way, this is no joke
だからこそ許せない 完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
That's why I can't forgive an imperfect you
自分を許せない 誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I can't forgive myself, accepting no one stronger than you
誰かが信じ崇めてる まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Worshipped by all, truly the strongest and invincible idol
弱点なんて見当たらない
No weaknesses to be found
一番星を宿している
The brightest star resides in you
弱いところなんて見せちゃ駄目だ
Showing any weakness is forbidden
知られたくないことは隠して
Hide what you don't want known
唯一無二だ抜け出しちゃいやいや
One and only, don't you dare slip away
それこそ本物の愛
That is true love
得意の笑顔で濁すマリア 隠しきるこの秘密だけは
Blurring with a practiced smile, keeping this secret hidden
愛してるって嘘で摘むキャリア これこそ私なりの愛だ
Building a career on "I love you" lies—that is my way of love
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア ルビーを隠したこの瞼
Flowing sweat, pure aqua; rubies hidden beneath my eyelids
歌い踊り舞い私はマリア そう嘘はとびっきりの愛だ
Singing and dancing, I am Maria; yes, lying is the greatest love
誰かに愛されたことも誰かのこと愛したこともない
I've never been loved by anyone, nor loved anyone myself
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること信じている
I believe that someday my lies will become the truth
いつかきっと全部手に入れる 私はそう欲張りなアイドル
Someday I'll get it all, I am such a greedy idol
等身大でみんなのことちゃんと愛したいから
Because I want to truly love everyone as my true self
今日も嘘をつくの この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
I lie again today, wishing for the day these words come true
それでもまだ君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
Even so, I still couldn't tell you and you alone
ああ やっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is definitely no lie
愛してる
I love you
ああ やっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is definitely no lie
愛してる
I love you
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ 呼び合う声を合図に
Parade, parade, parade! It's time to shine, taking our calling voices as our cue!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 探しに行く スタートは何回だって
Parade, parade, parade! We're going to search, no matter how many starts we take!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ 悔しさも愛しさも連れておいで
Parade, parade, parade! It's time to shine, bring along your regrets and your love!
風、夢、羽 飛び立てば ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し 君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
Wind, dreams, wings—if we take flight, our modest prayers become light, an endless sign. Finding you is something I can be proud of. From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade, Parade!
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
思いがけず結び合った
Unexpectedly bound together—
ほら 今
look, now,
迷子は “僕等” になった
the lost children have become "us."
パレード パレード パレード
Parade, parade, parade!
輝くんだよ
It's time to shine!
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring your regrets and your love along,
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
with wind, dreams, and wings to take flight!
ささやかな祈りは 光
Simple prayers become light,
終わりなき兆し
an endless omen.
君を見つけたこと
Finding you
胸を張れるよ
is something to be proud of.
ここから これから
From here, from now on—
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
まだ頼りない予感を
Singing songs with uncertain feelings—
歌おう 恥ずかしさなんかないよ
there's nothing to be embarrassed about!
誰も解けない イマジナリー
An imaginary world no one can solve,
いつかまた逢える おまじない
a spell to meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
A story that started from zero on that day—
数えきれない ことのは 数えるような想いじゃないさ
not feelings you can count with mere words.
ほら 今
Look, now,
僕らを一つと呼ぼう
let's call "us" as one!
パレード パレード パレード
Parade, parade, parade!
美しいんだよ
It's so beautiful—
許し合える 刹那 夜はきらめく
moments of forgiveness making the night sparkle.
雨 晴れ カレイド またとない空
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope, a one-of-a-kind sky.
相応しい旅路とは 君と在ることさ
A fitting journey means being right by your side.
君と在ることなんだ
Yes, being right by your side.
「ただいま」を聞けば
Hearing "I'm home"
「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
and shouting "Welcome back"—
当たり前じゃないか
isn't that just natural?
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! Shine on!
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
Filling the darkness are you and I!
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ 悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Parade, parade, parade! Shine on! Bring your regrets and your love along!
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ ささやかな祈りは 光
Riding the wind, dreams, wings, take flight! Simple prayers become light.
終わりなき兆し 君と飛び込んでいく 素敵なスタートさ
An endless omen. Diving in with you—what a wonderful start!
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade, Parade!
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
はい、というわけで、「Our Bright Parade」、アイドル衣装、そしてジャケットの衣装、2つ目ですね！
Yes! So, "Our Bright Parade," the idol outfit, and now the jacket outfit makes two!
1つ目、1つ目って来たら、まあ、そういうわけで、ええ、みんな見てこのジャケット、可愛いでしょう？
Since there's a first and a second, well, everyone, look at this jacket! Isn't it cute?
ちょっと同じ衣装なんだけど、ジャケットがあるだけでさ、全然違うイメージになるよね。
It's the same outfit, but just having the jacket gives it a totally different vibe, right?
すごいさ、なんか、いっぱいのお衣装をいっぺんに貰った感じがして、ドキドキしちゃう。
It feels like I got so many outfits all at once, it makes my heart race!
みんなこれもチェックしてね。
Make sure to check this out too, everyone!
はい、というわけで、ええ、ここね、みんな待ってたかな？グッズもあるよ！それも見ててこ、ポン！
Yes! So, have you all been waiting for this? There are goods too! Let's take a look—bam!
今年もあります、え、グッズ、え、誕生日記念2024誕生日記念フルセット、グッズ4種！
We have them this year too! The Birthday Celebration 2024 Full Set, 4 types of goods!
「アイドルそらちゃん」ラバーマット、そらと証明書、そらとIDカードホルダー、一緒に おでかけそらちゃんぬいぐるみ ピンクパーカー衣装、ボイス2種。
'Idol Sora-chan' rubber mat, Sora & ID certificate, Sora & ID card holder, plushie in pink hoodie, and 2 voice packs.
え、フルセットの方の購入特典は直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード！是非みんなゲットしてね！
And the purchase bonus for the full set is a bromid card with a handwritten sign and message! Be sure to get yours, everyone!
というわけで、詳しく見ていきましょうか。
So, let's take a closer look at them.
まず1つ目、「アイドルそらちゃん」ラバーマット！おるだん先生が描いてくれたラバーマットですよ！これめちゃくちゃ可愛いし、誕生日の時しかゲットできないから、みんなこれを使ってパソコンの作業とかもウキウキになってくれるととっても嬉しいです！こっちか！こっちだ！
First up is the 'Idol Sora-chan' rubber mat! Illustrated by Orudan-sensei! It's super cute, and you can only get it for my birthday, so I'd be so happy if you use it for PC work!
可愛いよね。
So cute.
こんな感じですね。
Something like this.
そして続いては、こちら！
And next is this!
そらとも証明書ということです。
It's a Soratomo Certificate.
なんか、証明書みたいなものが私は出したことがなかったなと思って、
I felt like I had never released something like a certificate before,
なんかめちゃくちゃ可愛い証明書、あとメッセージも書きました。
and it's a super cute certificate, plus I wrote a message on it.
見えるかどうか分からないけど、
I'm not sure if you can see it or not,
これを持ってるみんなは全員そらともだよ、
but everyone who has this is an official Soratomo,
ということで、ぜひゲットしてね。
so please make sure to get one!
そして次は、こちら！
And next, this!
そらともIDカードホルダー。
Soratomo ID Card Holder.
こちらシンプルなものになってますね、
This is a simple one, well,
IDカードホルダーなので、どこでもいつでも付けられるようなシンプルなもの。
since it's an ID card holder, it's simple enough to wear anytime, anywhere.
そしてね、あの例えば私よく、
And, for example, I...
あの、特典会とかやることがあるんですけど、
often have special events and things, right?
そういう時にはここに証明書を入れてきてもらえれば、
and if you put your certificate in here for those,
あ、そらともさんだってすぐに見つけることもできますね。
I can immediately spot you like, "Ah, a Soratomo!"
会社に使う人、学校で使う人、
People who use it for work, people for school,
いっぱいいると思います、ぜひぜひゲットしてください。
there are plenty of you, so please definitely get one!
そして次は、こちら！
And next is this!
え、これめっちゃ嬉しかったの！
I was so happy with this!
一緒におでかけそらちゃんぬいぐるみピンクパーカー衣装Ver.ということで、
"Let's Go Out Together! Sora-chan Plushie Pink Hoodie Ver."
ね、みんなさ、サムネのやつがさ、なんださ、あの、めちゃんこちびっ子じゃんってなってたの分かった？
You know, everyone saw the thumbnail and thought, "Oh, she looks so tiny!" Did you notice?
これ見て、全く同じでしょ？可愛いでしょう！
Look at this, it's exactly the same! Isn't it cute!
というわけで、こちらね、あの、帽子をつけたり外したりもできますし、
So, with this one, you can put the hood on or take it off,
チェーンがあるので、普通にそのカバンとかにもつけれるの。
and since it has a chain, you can attach it to bags normally.
そんなに大きくないサイズだから、
It's not a very big size, so
あの、大きいのを持ち歩くのは緊張しちゃうっていう子でも、ぜひ、あの、つけて私と一緒ににお出かけしてね。
even if you're nervous about carrying a large one around, please wear it and go out with me!
そして、続いては、こちら！
And next is this!
今回はシチュエーションボイスを2つご用意しました。
This time, we have prepared two situation voices.
シチュエーションボイス「ライブ前にきみと」、そしてシチュエーションボイス「一緒におでかけ」。
Situation voice "With You Before the Live", and situation voice "Going Out Together".
ということで、一緒にお出かけしたり、ライブ前にきみと喋ったり、そんなシチュエーションで楽しんでください。
So please enjoy those situations like going out together or talking with you before the live.
そして次は、こちら！
And next is this!
え、フルセット購入特典として、え、おるなせんせいの、描いてくださったチェキ風ブロマイドカードですね。
And as a full set purchase bonus, it's a Cheki-style bromide card drawn by Oruna-sensei.
こちらに、え、メッセージ入りで、全部書かせていただきます。
On this, with a message included, I will write on all of them.
是非みんな、たくさんたくさんみんなのために書きたいから、いっぱい、いっぱい待っててね。
Everyone, please wait a lot, because I want to write lots and lots for everyone!
そして、続いては、こちら！
And next is this!
え、誕生日フルセットの、え、詳細ですね。
And here are the details of the Birthday Full Set.
こちらラバーマット、証明書、IDカードホルダー、ぬいぐるみキーホルダー、ボイス2種、
Here: rubber mat, certificate, ID card holder, plushie keyholder, 2 voice types,
そしてそこにサインを書いたもの、私が実際に書いたものを皆さんにお届けできたらいいなと思っております。
and I hope to deliver items with my signature, which I actually wrote, to everyone.
21時頃、過ぎてる、
Around 21:00... it's past,
過ぎてる。けど、販売をスタートします。
it's past. But sales will start.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you for your support.
過ぎちゃったよ。まあいいか。
It passed. Oh well.
というわけで、
So,
まあね、ここでお知らせのものは最後なんですけど、
well, this is the last of the announcements here,
あ、この後最後にお知らせもあるからね、見てね。
Ah, there's also an announcement at the very end after this, so check it out.
で、そのあと、メンバーの方でも、
And after that, for members too,
なんかちょっと もうちょっとなんか表面、あるかもね。
there might be a bit more surface stuff.
メンバーの人は先に見れちゃうぞ。
Members get to see it first.
というわけで、ぜひ見に来てください。
So please come and check it out.
それでは最後の曲いきましょう！
Now let's go to the last song!
誇り高きアイドル
Proud Idol
私のこと知ってますか？
Do you know about me?
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute to you?
私の歌どうだろうな
How's my singing?
上手に歌えてますか？
Am I singing well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか
My outfit or my makeup,
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute?
振付とかファンサとかも
Even my choreography and fanservice,
喜んでもらえますか？
are you happy with them?
手は冷たくなって足は震える
My hands get cold and my feet tremble,
それでも戦いたい
even so, I want to fight
アイドルだから
because I'm an idol.
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of me,
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon too.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を 見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say "just an idol" without even looking!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't call working hard a given.
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force your image on me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉はこの世で一番大嫌いだ
The word "just an idol" is what I hate most in this world!
私のこと知ってますか？
Do you know about me?
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute to you?
私の歌どうだろうな
I wonder how my singing is.
上手に歌えてますか
Am I singing well?
衣装とかメイクとか
Are my outfit and makeup
可愛く見えてますか
looking cute enough?
振付とかファンサとかも
Are my choreography and fanservice
喜んでもらえますか
making you happy?
手は冷たくなって足は震える
My hands get cold and my legs shake,
それでも戦いたい
but still, I want to fight
アイドルだから
because I'm an idol.
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of us,
見下されるのも嫌いだ
and I hate being looked down upon.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を
Words like "just an idol"
見てもいないくせに言うな
don't say them when you haven't even watched.
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't call our hard work natural,
イメージとか強制するな
don't force your image on us.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
Words like "just an idol"
この世で一番大嫌いだ
are the things I hate most in this world.
プライベート見えないから分からないと思います
Since you can't see my private life, you probably don't know,
性格とか悪い方です 騙しちゃっていますか？
but my personality is pretty bad, have I been deceiving you?
でも本気です 本気なんです
But I'm serious, I really am.
ありのままの私を好きになって推して下さい
Please love and support the real me just as I am—
それってワガママですか？
is that being too selfish?
きっと可愛くない部分分かってる
I'm sure you know my uncute sides too,
それでも好かれていたい
but I still want to be loved
アイドルだから
because I'm an idol.
陰口言う奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who talk behind our backs,
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
and I hate constant excuses.
“こんなものか”という言葉を軽々しく口にするな
Don't casually say "is that all there is."
勝手に限界決めつけるな
Don't decide our limits on your own,
“アイドルなんか”という言葉はこの世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "just an idol" are what I hate most.
向かい風を切り裂け
Slash through the headwind,
誇り高きアイドル
proud idol,
目指そうぜ
let's aim for it.
応援がなければ活動できない
I can't be active without your support,
好きなことばかりじゃ生きてはいけない
and you can't live doing only what you like.
元気あげるはずがもらってばかりだし
I'm supposed to give you energy, but I always just receive it,
恩返しできる日まで待っていて
wait until the day I can repay you.
歓声が減っても
Even if the cheers decrease,
飽きられちゃっても
even if people get tired of me,
それでも笑っていたい
I still want to keep smiling
アイドルだから
because I'm an idol.
熱いファンの愛があって
With the passionate love of fans,
スタッフさんの愛があって
the love of the staff,
いつも家族の愛があって
and always the love of family,
生きてるアイドル
I am an idol living on.
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of us,
見下されるのも嫌いだ
and I hate being looked down upon.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を
Words like "just an idol"
見てもいないくせに言うな
don't say them when you haven't even watched.
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't call our hard work natural,
イメージとか強制するな
don't force your image on us.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
Words like "just an idol"
この世で一番大嫌いだ
are the things I hate most in this world.
はい、このあとは22時からファンクラブでリハーサル映像を公開します！
Right after this at 10 PM, rehearsal footage will be on the fan club!
みなさん可愛い新衣装ということでぜひ見てください！
It's in a cute new outfit, so please check it out!
そして、
And,
その次の日5月の16日21時からファンクラブの方で感想配信がありまして…新衣装のラフ画公開！オルダン先生からのメッセージ！
the next day on May 16th at 9 PM, there'll be an impressions stream... featuring rough sketches of the new outfit and a message from Ordan-sensei!
そしてこちら、なんと1曲目に歌いました「STILL TIME」がですね、ええ、今日の0時24時に…
And also, "STILL TIME", which I sang as the first song, will be...
配信、デジタル配信が決定しております！
released on streaming and digital platforms starting at midnight!
そして同じく0時にMVのプレミア公開もされますので、ぜひぜひこちらのほうお楽しみに！
Also at midnight, the MV premiere will go live, so please look forward to it!
そして、メン限でも何かちょっとした物があるかもね！よろしくお願いします！
And there might even be something special for members too! Thank you!